The past has a life of its own.
Beloved is a drama, thriller, horror film directed by Jonathan Demme.
After Paul D.
finds his old slave friend Sethe in Ohio and moves in with her and her daughter
Denver, a strange girl comes along by the name of "Beloved".
Sethe and Denver take her in and then strange things start to happen...
Sethe, played by Oprah Winfrey.
Paul D, played by Danny Glover.
Denver, played by Kimberly Elise.
Beloved, played by Thandiwe Newton.
Younger Sethe, played by LisaGay Hamilton.
Baby Suggs, played by Beah Richards.
Beloved is a 1998 American Gothic psychological horror drama film directed by Jonathan
Demme and starring Oprah Winfrey, Danny Glover, and Thandiwe Newton.
Based on Toni Morrison's 1987 novel of the same name, the plot centers on a former slave after the American
Civil War, her haunting by a poltergeist, and the visitation of her reincarnated daughter.
This was the first film produced by Harpo Films.
Beloved received an Oscar nomination for Best Costume Design for Colleen Atwood.
The film garnered mostly positive reviews, and both Danny Glover and Kimberly Elise
received praise for their performances, but was a box office bomb.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, loss of
loved one, affectation, slavery, poltergeist.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.